<Chapter Label="Functions">
<Heading>Functions</Heading>

Here we include a list of all functions that are provided to the User.<P/>

<Section Label="Wreath Product Decomposition">
<Heading>Wreath Product Decomposition</Heading>

The returned embeddings, i.e. wreath product decompositions, map into specialised wreath product representations,
the ones obtained by <C>WreathProduct</C>.
The main way for the User to look at a wreath product in a "human-readable" way
is either by using an isomorphism from such a specialised wreath product representation
to a generic representation via <C>IsomorphismWreathProduct</C> or by using the low-level function <C>ListWreathProductElement</C>.

<ManSection>
<Meth Name="WreathProductDecomposition" Arg="G[, optrec]"/>

<Description>
Let <A>G</A> be a group or a recog node,
and <A>optrec</A> be an options record.
Returns fail or a wreath product decomposition of <A>G</A>, i.e. an embedding from <A>G</A> to a natural wreath product,
unless the <A>debug</A> option is set to true (see below).

The following components of <A>optrec</A> are supported.
Many more technical components are supported, however, they might be due to change during development.
We therefore refer advanced users to the comments in the code to see all available options.
Suppose that <M>G \leq K \wr H</M> with <M>H \leq \textrm{Sym}(m)</M>.

<List>
<Mark><C>action</C></Mark>
<Item>
<K>"product action"</K> for permutation group, assume product action <P/>
<K>"imprimitive action"</K> for permutation or matrix group, assume imprimitive action <P/>
<K>fail</K> no assumptions <E>DEFAULT</E> <P/>
</Item>
<Mark><C>assumeSimpleBaseComponent</C></Mark>
<Item>
<K>true</K> assume <M>K</M> is non-abelian simple <E>DEFAULT</E> <P/>
<K>false</K> no assumptions <P/>
</Item>
<Mark><C>debug</C></Mark>
<Item>
<K>true</K> return record containing "res", "data" and "options": <P/>
    <List>
    <Item> <K>"res"</K> is true if embedding was computed, otherwise fail </Item>
    <Item> <K>"data"</K> is record containing all intermediate results of the computation </Item>
    <Item> <K>"options"</K> is a copy of the used options record in the computation </Item>
    </List>
<K>false</K> return fail or embedding <E>DEFAULT</E> <P/>
</Item>
</List>
</Description>

</ManSection>

</Section>

</Chapter>