<Chapter Label="Intro">
<Heading>Introduction</Heading>

This chapter serves as an introduction and showcases some highlights of the package &WPrecog;.

<Section Label="Intro Overview">
<Heading>Overview</Heading>

The package &WPrecog;
<Alt Only="HTML"><![CDATA[
(<b><u>W</u></b>reath <b><u>P</b></u>roduct <b><u>Recog</b></u>nition)
]]>
</Alt><Alt Not="HTML">
(<E>W</E>reath <E>P</E>roduct <E>Recog</E>nition).
</Alt>
provides recognition methods for groups abstractly isomorphic to certain (subgroups of) wreath products. <P/>

Assume we are given as input a black box group <M>G</M> which is isomorphic to a (subgroup of) wreath product. In certain cases, we can compute a wreath product decomposition of the input group, that is an embedding from the group into a natural wreath product where elements are encoded component-wise. For example, <M>G</M> can be a matrix group of Aschbacher class C2 or a primitive group of type PA. The main command is provided via <C>WreathProductDecomposition</C>. <P/>

For instance, the computation of a wreath product decomposition of <M>\textrm{PSL}(3,3) \wr E(4)</M> represented as a primitive group of type PA acting on <M>13^4 = 28\,561</M> points takes less than half a second. This yields an effective mapping into an imprimitive wreath product acting on <M>13 \cdot 4 = 52</M> points.
</Section>

<Section Label="Primitive Groups of type PA">
<Heading>Primitive Groups of type PA</Heading>

We provide an example computation of a wreath product decomposition for a primitive permutation group <M>G</M> of type PA isomorphic to <M>\textrm{PSL}(3,3) \wr E(4)</M>.
First, we load the package and an additional utility file that helps us to create pseudo-random generators. We also disable the additional display of information provided by the recog package.

<Example><![CDATA[
# Load package and utility file for constructing pseudo-random generators, etc.
gap> LoadPackage("WPrecog", false);;
gap> ReadPackage("WPrecog", "examples/Utils.gi");;
gap> SetInfoLevel(InfoRecog, 0);
]]></Example>

Next, we construct the components of the wreath product.
The base component <M>K = \textrm{PSL}(3,3)</M> acts on <M>n = 13</M> points and the top component <M>E(4)</M> acts on <M>m = 4</M> points.

<Example><![CDATA[
# Construct components
gap> K := PrimitiveGroup(13, 7); # PSL(3,3)
L(3, 3)
gap> n := NrMovedPoints(K);
13
gap> Length(GeneratorsOfGroup(K));
2
gap> H := TransitiveGroup(4, 2);
E(4) = 2[x]2
gap> m := NrMovedPoints(H);
4
gap> Length(GeneratorsOfGroup(H));
2
]]></Example>

Now, we construct the wreath product <M>W = K \wr H</M>.
The native &GAP; command <C>WreathProductProductAction(K, H)</C> creates a wreath product in product action acting on <M>13^4 = 28\,561</M> points.
Since &GAP; knows that we created <M>W</M> as a wreath product,
we can directly access the components of elements.
Therefore, we later need to disguise the group on the computer so &GAP; does not have direct access to this information.
Moreover, the constructed generators are highly structured.
The first <M>8</M> generators are the generators of the base group,
and the last <M>2</M> generators are the generators of the top group.
<Example><![CDATA[
# Construct black box group G isomorphic to wreath product W
gap> W := WreathProductProductAction(K, H);
<permutation group of size 3978949139103744 with 10 generators>
gap> NrMovedPoints(W);
28561
gap> HasWreathProductInfo(W);
true

# generators of first base component
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, W.1);
[ (1,10,4)(6,9,7)(8,12,13), (), (), (), () ]
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, W.5);
[ (1,3,2)(4,9,5)(7,8,12)(10,13,11), (), (), (), () ]

# generators of second base component
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, W.2);
[ (), (1,10,4)(6,9,7)(8,12,13), (), (), () ]
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, W.6);
[ (), (1,3,2)(4,9,5)(7,8,12)(10,13,11), (), (), () ]

# generators of top component
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, W.9);
[ (), (), (), (), (1,4)(2,3) ]
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, W.10);
[ (), (), (), (), (1,2)(3,4) ]
]]></Example>

Now, we construct the black box group <M>G</M> isomorphic to <M>W = K \wr H</M>.
For this we use utility functions provided by "examples/Utils.gi" in this package.
In order to disguise the group on the computer,
we use a utility command <C>RandomGroup</C> to generate pseudo-random generators.
Afterwards, we use a pseudo-random permutation generated by the utility command
<C>QuickRandomPermutedList</C> to conjugate these generators.
Therefore, &GAP; has no longer access to the components of wreath product elements,
even provided that we know the wreath product <M>W</M>.
<Example><![CDATA[
# Construct black box group G isomorphic to wreath product W
gap> G := RandomGroup(W)^PermList(QuickRandomPermutedList(n^m));
<permutation group with 15 generators>
gap> HasWreathProductInfo(G);
false
gap> ListWreathProductElement(W, G.1);
fail
]]></Example>

Finally, we use the main command of this package, <C>WreathProductDecomposition</C> on the group <M>G</M>. We tell the computer to assume that <M>G</M> is a primitive group of type PA.
The return value is an embedding <M>\varphi</M> from <M>G</M> to a natural wreath product <M>R = \textrm{Sym}(13) \wr \textrm{Sym}(4)</M> acting imprimitively on <M>13 \cdot 4 = 52</M> points.
The elements in <M>R</M> can be viewed component-wise.
<Example><![CDATA[
# Wreath Product Decomposition
gap> phi := WreathProductDecomposition(G, rec(
>     action := "product action"
> ));;
gap> R := Range(phi);
<permutation group of size 36085481721713375974666734560870400000000 with 10 generators>
gap> NrMovedPoints(R);
52
gap> HasWreathProductInfo(R);
true
gap> ListWreathProductElement(R, ImageElm(phi, G.1));
[
(1,9,10,5,13,3,11,4,12,6,2,7,8),
(1,2)(3,11,6,9)(4,7,5,12)(8,13),
(1,8,9,6)(2,11)(3,5)(4,12,13,10),
(1,10)(2,8,11,12)(4,5)(6,7,13,9),
()
]
]]></Example>
</Section>

</Chapter>